

- **)** +20 109 699 3853
- www.johnydesigns.com
- Cairo, Egypt.

COVER LETTER

DEAR SIR / MADAM,

My name is John, I am a DevOps Engineer offering 9 years of experience, an expert in Windows OS, MAC OSX & Linux, with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevOps culture, currently I am focusing on developing apps, Full-Stack development and cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a Sr. System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management Including win-servers (2003, 2008, 2012), Mac server, firewall Linux server, Render Farm, network management, NAS, SAN, LAN, WAN, RAID, ticketing systems, software distribution, updates, patching virus protection, and imaging.

Then I became an IT Project Manager, which was more managerial level than technical Starting with determine project objectives, predict resources needed, assign tasks, monitor progress until the project is delivered on time, during this time i was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

And currently I am a DevOps Engineer providing level 3 technical support for Linux and Windows users, developing applications with python.

Besides my main experience in the IT field, I have been using Adobe Products for the past 12 years and Front-End for the past 5 years, I am not a Graphic Designer but I have a quite good taste and freelance experience doing websites, logos, mobile apps, leaflets & retouch, you are welcome to check my website johnydesigns.com.

I have enclosed my cover letter for your review. I appreciate your time.

Sincerely,

John Bedeir DevOps Engineer



+20 109 699 3853

 \bowtie john.bedeir@gmail.com

www.johnydesigns.com

Cairo, Egypt.

Summary

I am a DevOps Engineer offering 9 years of experience, an expert in Linux, Windows OS & MAC OSX with a strong development background.

Plus a quite good experience in Web Design.

Career Objective

Currently, I am focusing on Python, Containers & Cloud Services and my aim is to master DevOps & Automation.

Sr. Sys Admin

Linux Sys Admin

Python

DevOps

Automation

Work Experiences

Jan 2020 - Current

DevOps Engineer (CAS-SDR)

Orange Business Services

Orange is a French multinational telecommunication corporation.

- Critical Application Support & Service Delivery Tool
- · Working on ways to automate and improve development and release processes

Cairo, Egypt

- Working with software developers and software engineers to ensure that development follows established processes
- Working in AGILE.
- Front-End Development Tools: VS Code, WAMP, Git, GitLab.
- **Project 1** SDMP: Making it responsive using Bootstrap & CSS3
- Project 2 Survey Bot: Building a website from scratch following Orange branding guidelines using XD & Front-End Development.

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

IT PROJECT MANAGER

Yaryor Technologies

Dubai, UAE

YARYOR is a small company, mostly working on projects that include new technologies like Robotics, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Digital Signage, Web Development, and Mobile applications.

- · IT Manager
- Determine and define project scope and objectives
- · Predict resources needed to reach objectives
- · Monitor progress and make adjustments as needed
- Measure project performance to identify areas for improvement
- Web Development: Front-End & Adobe XD

Mar 2016 - Apr 2018

SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Plus500 BG

▼ Sofia, Bulgaria

Plus500 is a huge international firm providing online trading, working there was a great opportunity I started there with the Technical Support team then I got promoted to Senior IT providing High-level Support for Windows OS in two offices.

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.

Expertise

Linux, Windows & MAC

Bash Scripting

Vmware, Parallels & Virtualbox

Web Hosting: cPanel

Hardware replacement

Network Installation & troubleshooting

NIC Teaming / Renderfarm

HTML5 / CSS3

Languages

Arabic	Native	
English	Fluent	
Bulgarian	Conversational	

- · Performs other related duties as assigned.

Work Experiences

Jan 2014 - Jul 2015

SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Aroma Studios



AROMA is an extraordinary company for media production in the middle east, I got the opportunity for working as a Senior IT with a team of IT providing 24/7 coverage with level 2 crossover platform support Windows OS, Mac OSX, and Linux.

- Level 1 2 Support for all instance (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure linux and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure pending tasks have been solved.
- Check Kaspersky endpoint security management console and ensure there are no alerts.
- Check the Servers & Renderfarm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

Sep 2011 - Dec 2013 SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Arabcomed



The Arab Company for Medical Products is a factory for manufacturing pharmaceutical this was my first full-time job after graduation providing level 1 help desk support and Create new designs and editing the company website.

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Create New Designs for the next coming product
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Check the Server room temperature.



Education and Certificates

2015 - 2019

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

Technical University, Sofia, Bulgaria.

2007 - 2011

Bachelors in Computer Science

Future Academy, Cairo, Egypt.

Volunteering Activity

Member of IT Committee

Enactus Organization, Cairo, Egypt.

CERTIFICATES & SELF-STUDIES

ICDL	(Certified)
MCSA	(Self-Study)
HTML/ CSS3	(Self-Study)
JavaScript	(Self-Study)
Bash Scripting	(Self-Study)
RHCSA	(Self-Study)
Git	(Self-Study)
Docker	(Self-Study)
Python	(Self-Study)
Vagrant	(Self-Study)

OTHER SKILLS & APPS

Ubuntu, Mint & CentOs

MYSQL, Apache, Nginx

VS Code, Spyder, Atom & **Brackets**

Grsync, Timeshift

Untangle network security

Remote Apps & **PDQ Deploy**

WDS & NetInstall

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesigns

Adobe After Effects

Adobe XD

Adobe Photoshop (Certified)